Today I am going to show you how to make
your very own functional black hole right
at home. Please remember, this is a
completely informative video. Do not try
this at home unless your home is located
at least fifty thousand light-years away
from the nearest populated solar system.
To get started, you are going to need a
few basic supplies. First, you will need a
star, and no, you cannot use our sun. It
is way too small. It does not have the
mass, and frankly, we are currently using
it to live. You are looking for a star
with at least fifteen to twenty times the
mass of our sun. A blue supergiant is
perfect for this. Pro tip: tag that one
strong friend who always helps you move
furniture because you are going to need
their help dragging it back to your
garage. You will also need a giant
planetary-scale French coffee press, three
desk fans for cooling, and a little
wooden house just for good measure. Let us
get started. Once you have successfully
stolen a star from the cosmos, you have
two options. Option one is the natural
method. This is great for those of you who
have a lot of patience and billions of
years of free time. Basically, you just
wait for the star to run out of nuclear
fuel. Once it stops fusing hydrogen into
helium, the outward pressure drops and the
core collapses under its own immense
gravity. It is a completely organic,
non-GMO process. The outer layers will
blast away in a beautiful supernova, which
will instantly vaporize you and your
entire zip code, leaving behind a
beautiful, locally sourced singularity.
But who has a few billion years to wait,
right? Let us talk about option two.
Option two is for the impatient crafter.
We are going to manually compress our star
below its Schwarzschild radius. The
Schwarzschild radius is just a fancy
science term for the point where an object
is squished so small that light cannot
even escape its gravity. Just take your
giant coffee press, toss your star inside,
add your fans and your little house. Why?
Because DIY is about expressing your
personal truth. Now, push down on the
plunger. Ta-da, you have manually
triggered gravitational collapse. You now
have a homemade functional black hole. Now
that you have your black hole, let us
talk about maintenance. It is incredibly
low maintenance. You do not have to water
it. In fact, it will water itself by
violently consuming your plumbing. It is
also the perfect garbage disposal.
Leftover dinner, junk mail, unpaid parking
tickets, just toss them into the
accretion disk. Look at that
spaghettification. So aesthetic.
One major safety tip. I highly recommend
not getting too close to the event
horizon. If you cross that threshold, not
even light can escape, meaning your
physical form will be stretched infinitely
across the cosmos, and you will
experience time standing completely still
while you are crushed into an infinitely
dense point of nothingness, which would
really ruin your weekend plans. And that
is it for today's tutorial. If you enjoyed
this video and successfully created a
tear in the fabric of the universe, please
give this video a thumbs up. Let me know
in the comments below what star you used
for your black hole, and do not forget to
tag the friend who helped you carry it.
Subscribe for more life hacks, and I will
see you in the next one, assuming space
and time still exist by then. Bye.