Imagine NASA calls you tomorrow and says,
Good news! We found a volunteer for a very
important mission.
You ask, What's the mission?
They reply, We're throwing you into Jupiter.
Before you can say no, you're already heading
toward the largest planet in the solar
system. Now, since Jupiter is basically a
giant ball of gas, you might be thinking,
Wait, if it's all gas, couldn't I just fall
straight through it and come out the other
side? Fair question. Let's find out.
As you approach Jupiter,
the first thing you'll notice is its size.
Pictures don't do it justice.
Jupiter is absolutely enormous.
Jupiter would be about the size of a
basketball. And that giant basketball is
pulling on you with some serious gravity.
Soon you're falling faster and faster.
At first it's exciting, then it's terrifying.
Then it's the kind of speed where your brain
stops caring about numbers altogether.
Finally, you reach Jupiter's clouds.
And honestly, this is where the fun adventure
part ends. The colorful clouds look beautiful
from space, but they're hiding one of the
most violent environments in the solar
system. Jupiter's winds can reach over 600
kilometers per hour.
That's strong enough to make the worst
hurricane on Earth look like a a windy
afternoon.
And then there's the Great Red Spot,
a storm so huge that Earth could fit inside
it. Imagine being tossed around inside a
hurricane bigger than an entire planet,
not ideal. As you keep falling,
something strange happens.
The deeper you go, the thicker the atmosphere
becomes. You expected empty gas.
Instead, it starts feeling more like diving
into an ocean. Then an even thicker ocean.
Then an even thicker ocean.
At this point, Jupiter is basically saying,
"Oh, you thought this would be easy?"The
pressure
millions of times.
Your body would be crushed long before
reaching the deeper layers.
But let's pretend you're wearing the greatest
space suit ever invented.
A completely indestructible suit,
because otherwise this video would end way
too early. As you descend further,
the hydrogen around you transforms into
something called metallic hydrogen.
This stuff is wild.
It's hydrogen squeezed so hard that it starts
acting like liquid metal.
Imagine taking the lightest element in the
universe and compressing it until physics
starts doing weird things.
By now you're entering a region no human has
ever seen. No space group.
has ever visited, and no machine we've built
could survive. But our magical,
indestructible suit keeps us going.
Eventually, you approach Jupiter's center.
And here's the surprising part:
you still haven't found a surface.
No giant, rocky floor.
No place to stand.
No sign saying"Welcome to Jupiter!"Just more
crushing pressure and unimaginable heat.
Temperatures near the center may be hotter
than the surface of the sun,
which is a very bad place for a sightseeing
tour. Now let's answer the big question:
can you fall all the way through Jupiter and
pop out the other side?
No. Even with your imaginary indestructible
suit, Jupiter's gravity would keep pulling
you toward the center.
You'd fall past it, then get pulled back,
then past it again, back and forth,
back and forth, like the world's most
dangerous playground swing.
Eventually, the dense material inside Jupiter
would slow you down until you settled near
the center.
Congratulations, you now live inside Jupiter.
Unfortunately, your neighbors are crushing
pressure and temperatures hotter than the
sun. So what happens if you fall into
Jupiter? You don't land,
you don't pass through, and you definitely
don't come out the other side.
Instead, you discover that a planet made of
gas can be just as deadly as a planet made of
rock. Jupiter isn't a giant fluffy cloud,
it's a gravity-powered nightmare wrapped in
beautiful colors, and once you start falling,
there's no coming back.