Imagine you have a time machine.
Not a normal one, a perfect time machine.
One that can travel back through every moment in
history. You go back one year, then 1,000 years,
then a million.
Dinosaurs appear, then the earth disappears
completely. You keep going.
The sun hasn't formed yet.
The Milky Way doesn't exist.
No stars, no planets, no galaxies.
Just a hot, dense universe shrinking smaller and
smaller as you travel backward through time.
You keep going. 10 billion years,
12 billion years, 13 billion years, and then...
You reach the Big Bang.
The moment everything began.
The moment space itself was born.
the moment time itself started ticking.
Naturally, the next question is:
What was there before that?
And this is where things get weird,
because according to our current understanding of
physics, The answer might actually be nothing.
not empty space. not darkness.
Not a giant explosion waiting to happen.
Nothing. Because the Big Bang wasn't an explosion
that happened inside space.
The Big Bang was the creation of space itself.
Think about it this way:
Asking what was before the Big Bang might be like
asking,"What's north of the North Pole?"
At first it sounds like a reasonable question,
But the closer you look, the less sense it makes.
The North Pole is the northernmost point.
There is no north beyond it.
Similarly, if time itself began at the Big Bang,
There may have been no"before"for anything to
exist in, No time. No events.
No waiting. know before.
But not every scientist agrees that's the end of
the story.
Some theories suggest there actually was something
before the Big Bang.
One idea is called the big bounce.
According to this theory, our universe may not be
the first universe.
Instead, a previous universe existed long before
ours. Over trillions of years, it slowly collapsed
inward, smaller. Denser.
hotter. until eventually it reached an extreme
state and bounced outward again.
Creating the universe we see today.
In this picture, the Big Bang wasn't the
beginning. It was just a restart button.
Like the universe taking a cosmic breath,
in Out. again and again forever.
But wait! It gets even stranger.
Another theory suggests our universe might be only
one bubble in an enormous cosmic ocean.
Imagine boiling water.
Bubbles constantly appear and disappear.
Now replace the water with an unimaginably vast
reality.
and replace the bubbles with entire universes.
each one having its own stars, its own galaxies,
maybe even its own laws of physics.
Our universe could simply be one bubble among
countless others.
And if that's true, The Big Bang may have been the
moment our particular bubble was born.
Not the moment everything began.
Then there's perhaps the strangest possibility of
all: Some physicists think time itself may be an
illusion. At the deepest level of reality,
there may be no past. No future.
No flow of time at all.
What we experience as time could simply emerge
from something more fundamental that we don't yet
understand.
In that case, asking what happened before the Big
Bang could be like asking what color the number 7
is. The question itself may not fit the rules of
reality. And here's the truth:
Nobody knows which answer is correct.
Not yet.
The Big Bang is where our current theories begin
to break down. General relativity tells one story.
Quantum Mechanics tells another:
And when we push both theories back to the very
beginning, The math stops making sense.
Somewhere beyond that wall lies one of the
greatest mysteries in science.
So what was there before the Big Bang?
Maybe nothing. Maybe another universe.
Maybe an infinite cycle of cosmic rebirths.
Maybe countless universes beyond our own.
Or maybe the question itself has no answer because
time didn't exist yet,
The most incredible part is that right now,
somewhere on Earth, scientists are searching for
clues. Studying Ancient Light
Building powerful telescopes.
trying to uncover evidence that could reveal what
happened before the beginning.
And perhaps one day, humanity will finally know.
Until then, The biggest mystery in the universe
remains the one that came before the universe
itself.
(Transcribed by UniScribe (https://www.uniscribe.co). Upgrade to remove this message.)